# JOSEPH MEUS

# Denver, Co 80204

Phone: 563-581-3605| Email: meusjoseph21@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-meus-4b8b071b4/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-meus-4b8b071b4/</a> GitHub:

https://github.com/meusjoseph21 | Portfolio: https://meusjoseph21.github.io/portfolio-update-hw7/

#### SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with a preference towards front-end development with an education in biology and a determination to keep expanding skills and experience. Capable at working in a high stress environment and meeting tight deadlines all while creating intuitive and effective applications. Well known for determination, willingness to learn, and problem solving in the face of adversity.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Language: HTML, CSS, Javascript(ES6), JQuery, Node.js, Materialize, Bootstrap

**Applications: VSCode** 

Language: mySQL, Sequelize Applications: mySQL, Postman

Language: MongoDB Applications: Robo3T

#### **PROJECTS**

Meal-Matcher|https://github.com/jessicaano92/meal\_matcher\_javascript\_ajax|https://jessicaano92.github.io/meal\_matcher\_javascript\_ajax/

- Meal Matcher is a recipe book that searches for recipes from the MealDB recipe API based on the ingredients a user searches. Users can then save and remove recipes from their recipe book.
- Wireframing design, Developing Javascript functions, implementing CSS layout
- Javascript(ES6), Materialize, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

#### HotelMotel|https://github.com/ryanwit/hotel motel|https://hotelmotel.herokuapp.com/

- Hotel Motel is a property management application designed specifically for smaller boutique style hotels. This application allows hotel employees to create reservations easily all with a couple clicks of their mouse.
- Wireframing design, Developing Javascript functions, implementing CSS layout, Developing Sequelize database, and creating HTML/API routes
- Javascript(ES6), Materialize, HTML, CSS, Sequelize, Express-handlebars, Vanta.js, Express

# Eat-Da-Burgers|https://github.com/meusjoseph21/express-burgers-handlebars|https://polar-shore-82853.herokuapp.com/

- Eat-Da-Burger is an Express-handlebars application that allows users to make a burger, eat the burger and continue creating more.
- Following MVC file structure, CSS design using bootstrap, and routing handlebars to work with mySQL
- Javascript(ES6), Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, mySQL, Express-handlebars, Express

#### EXPERIENCE

# Ski Technician One Stop Ski Shop

2019 - 2020

Steamboat Springs, Colorado

Helped streamline the rental process in order to get customers in and out as fast as possible, worked as a team with my coworkers, innovated new ways to market our company, managed data including ski rentals, monetary gains, and customer information.

Key Accomplishments:

- Over \$100,000.00 in company revenue during the holiday season.
- Increased web revenue in and out of ski season.
- Apart of implementing ipad based rental application

**Server** 2018– 2019

### **Grimaldis Pizzeria**

Brookfield. Wisconsin

Worked in a team to optimize the dining experience, managed money and other customer information including weekly newsletter sign ups, kept composure in a high stress environment, and worked quickly and calmly to deliver the best possible experience for customers.

Key Accomplishments:

- Promoted from host to desired position as a server within three weeks of employment.
- Helped teach other employees proper techniques for bussing and managing table counts in a timely and effective manner.

# Head Counselor Gold Arrow Camp

2017- 2020

Lakeshore, California

Managed team members and campers on a bi-weekly basis, ensured that scheduling would not only be efficient but also provide a memorable experience for counselors and campers alike, and practiced leadership and communication skills with parents and counselors alike.

Key Accomplishments:

- No negative reviews from counselors and campers over the 2019 summer sessions.
- Promotion from Group Counselor to Head Counselor in the 2018 summer season.
- A part of American Camp Association for four year and took part in implementing Mental Health Certification for all Group Counselors in the 2019 summer season.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bootcamp Certificate:** Denver University, Denver Colorado

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Biology Degree: Carroll University, Waukesha Wisconsin

A 4 year undergraduate program that focused on the basics of biological sciences including human biology, microbiology, zoology, ecology, environmental sciences, and chemistry and provided an overview of other disciplines including mathematics(calculus), history, and data analytics(python).